There's a lot to learn with making background
transactions efficient. But the good news is that Android
gives you the Sync Manager framework that implements
many of these best practices. You utilize that framework
by implementing a sync adapter. The framework, originally
introduced in Android 2.0 Eclair or Android API level
5, allows Android applications to leverage the same
basic framework that Google apps use for efficient synchronization.
Ultimately, it's a centralized place to put all
of the device data transfers in one place.
So that they all be scheduled intelligently by
the OS. In other words, that's one big cookie.
Android Sync Manager handles synchronization requests using sync
adapters. The Sync Manager batches and time shifts
these requests when possible to allow your data
transfers to be scheduled with transfers from other apps,
all working towards the goal of reducing the
number of times the system has to switch on
the radio. If your device has less memory,
it will schedule fewer simultaneous synchs. The Synch Manager
also takes care of things like checking for
network connectivity before initiating transfers and retrying downloads when
connectivity is dropped. The synchronization framework works with content
providers for two way synchronization and leverages the Android
account manager to provide synchronization services that are
tied to accounts. Our application will do neither
of these things, but we'll still have to
deal with some of the complexity of these features.
This can make SyncAdapter seem daunting at first.
What does the SyncManager do to help you fetch
data from the network? Does it schedule your
network jobs with other apps, implement a synchronization protocol,
store account information, or has logic to retry
your request? Select all of these that match.